(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
じょーじょーゆーじょー ばじまじかいちょー
Amazing friendship, super high spirits!
なななななななな
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
ヒャダインのじょーじょーゆーじょー はいっちゃいましょー 君はベストフレンド
Hyadain's amazing friendship! Let's get into it, you're my best friend!
ちょっとふざけてみたら もっとふざけ返してくれ
If I mess around a bit, mess around even more back at me.
なななな
Na-na-na-na
居心地ったらないじゃない
It's so comfortable, isn't it?
嫌なことあったって さっそ忘れてっちゃうんだ
Even if something bad happens, I'll forget it right away.
なななな
Na-na-na-na
いつだってジャンジャンやりましょう
Let's always do it with a bang!
24時間一緒でも問題ない まるで双子か親子かクローンかサイボーグ
Even 24 hours together is no problem. Like twins, or parent and child, or clones, or cyborgs.
こんな洒落た関係 必要とかなくなってない? それとこれとは全く全く別問題
This stylish relationship, is it even necessary anymore? That's a completely different matter.
喧嘩しちゃった時も かなり凹んだ時も 一人でいたいような時も
Even when we fight, even when I'm really down, even when I want to be alone...
ふと気付けば近くにいるしなばもろとも
I suddenly realize you're nearby, sinking or swimming together.
なんでだろう そばにいたいんだ 君と一緒なら 楽しさ100倍さ
I wonder why? I want to be with you. If I'm with you, the fun is multiplied 100 times.
楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強フレンド
It's fun, it's too much fun. As expected of the strongest friend.
なののよ
Na-no-no-yo
やばいシンクロか
Crazy synchronization, huh?
いつもお騒がせ ご近所迷惑
Always causing a ruckus, bothering the neighbors.
今何時?
What time is it now?
エトネヨロレイヒ!
Etone yoloreihi!
わけわかんないない
I don't get it at all.
それどーしら 想像以上なんてゆーか最高 あだこだ言ってても友達はっしょい!
How's that? It's beyond imagination, like, the best! Whatever we say, friends are high-spirited!
じょーじょーゆーじょー ばじまじかいちょー
Amazing friendship, super high spirits!
なななななななな
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
おかころのじょーじょーゆーじょー2番をお聞きください！
Please listen to the 2nd verse of OkaKoro's Amazing Friendship!
同じテレビ見て メールで実況中継
Watching the same TV show, giving a live report via email.
なななな
Na-na-na-na
ＣＭ入れば電話タイム
If a commercial comes on, it's phone time.
遠くにいる時でも 近くに感じてるんだ
Even when we're far apart, I feel you close by.
なななな
Na-na-na-na
よろしくガンガン行きましょう
Let's keep going with all we've got.
ヤバい弁当忘れた完封して ヤバい命の源焼きそばパン
Oh no, I forgot my lunch, I'm toast! Oh no, the source of life, yakisoba bread!
ちょいと友達なんでしょゴムたいない それとこれとは全く全く別問題
Hey, we're friends, right? Like rubber? That's a completely different matter.
変な気は使わない 顔色なんか伺わない それでも傷つけたりしない
I don't use weird care, I don't look at your expression. But even so, I won't hurt you.
神様マジありがとうゲットできたマブダチ
God, thank you so much, I got a true friend.
やった！ おっしゃー!
Yay! Alright!
You are my friend!
最高潮 腹筋崩壊 涙出てくる 笑い疲れちゃうんだ
Peak excitement, my abs are collapsing! Tears coming out, I'm tired from laughing.
何しようか 何をしましょうか 尻取りレッツゴー!
What should we do? What shall we do? Shiritori, let's go!
ワー!
Waa!
なななな
Na-na-na-na
面倒だろ
It's a bother, right?
らぶこりに
To Love-Kori
なんだその生き物!
What is that creature?!
もう飽きた
I'm bored already.
マジかエトネヨロレイヒ!
Really? Etone yoloreihi!
意味わかんないない
It makes no sense.
それどーしら ともだちとかずっと くすぐったく思ってた でもでもやっぱ言えない
How's that? Thinking about "friends" and stuff for a long time was ticklish. But, but, I still can't say it...
Because
なななな
Na-na-na-na
はいっちゃいましょー 君はベストフレンド
Let's get into it, you're my best friend!
なんでだろう そばにいたいんだ 君と一緒なら 楽しさ100倍さ
I wonder why? I want to be with you. If I'm with you, the fun is multiplied 100 times.
楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強フレンド
It's fun, it's too much fun. As expected of the strongest friend.
なののよ
Na-no-no-yo
やばいシンクロか
Crazy synchronization, huh?
いつもお騒がせ ご近所迷惑
Always causing a ruckus, bothering the neighbors.
今何時?
What time is it now?
エトネヨロレイヒ!
Etone yoloreihi!
わけわかんないない
I don't get it at all.
それどーしら 想像以上なんてゆーか最高 あだこだ言ってても友達はっしょい!
How's that? It's beyond imagination, like, the best! Whatever we say, friends are high-spirited!
じょーじょーゆーじょー ばじまじかいちょー
Amazing friendship, super high spirits!
ちゃちゃらちゃっちゃらー
Cha-cha-ra-cha-cha-ra!
みんなー！おかころが来たぞー！
Everyone! OkaKoro is here!
来たぞー！
We're here!
うわー！来たぞ来たぞー！
Whoa! We're here, we're here!
来たぞ来たぞ来たぞ来たぞー！
We're here, we're here, we're here, we're here!
うわー、ありがとうー！見えてるよ、みんな見えてるよ！
Whoa, thank you! I can see you, I can see everyone!
ありがとう！みんな見えてるよ！
Thank you! I can see everyone!
ドキドキ…緊張…緊張…
My heart's pounding... I'm nervous... so nervous...
緊張…緊張だけど…緊張だね。
Nervous... I'm nervous, but... yeah, I'm nervous.
じゃ、えっと…改めてまして、ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆと…
Well, then... once again, I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers and...
戌神ころねと申しますー！
I'm Inugami Korone!
わー！わー！
Yay! Yay!
今日はね、おかころ2周年の3Dライブに来てくださって…
Thank you all for coming to our OkaKoro 2nd Anniversary 3D Live today!
ってーぺらぺらぺら…大丈夫か？
*stumble stumble* Are you okay?
て、皆さん、ありがとうございます！
Anyway, thank you everyone!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そうだった、1曲目…
That's right, for the first song...
いや、なんかね、お尻をね、ぶつけてね、飛んでくところがね…
Well, you know, when we bumped our butts together and went flying...
あ、そう！ぶつけようって言った。
Ah, right! We said let's bump them.
リハの時より飛んだなと思って。
I think we flew further than we did in rehearsal.
そうだね、おかゆ飛んでったね！バハン！ってなってさ。
You're right, Okayu went flying! Like 'BAM!'
そこが僕はね、すごいちょっと良かったなって思って。
I really liked that part.
ね。最後、みんな気づいた？ちょっとね、おかゆにチュウしたんだよ。気づいた？
Right. Did everyone notice the end? I gave Okayu a little kiss. Did you notice?
そうだよ！気づいた？
That's right! Did you notice?
気づいてない人の方が多いかもね。
Maybe most people didn't notice.
チュウしたんだよね。
I gave her a kiss.
そう。ということで…もう一回やる？あ、はい。
Yeah. So... should we do it again? Oh, okay.
同性ッキュ！
Gender-neutral kiss!
ということで、本日はこちらのハッシュタグ…
By the way, using today's hashtag...
「おかころ2周年3Dライブ」でたくさん呟いてくれたら嬉しいです。
We'd be happy if you could tweet a lot with #OkaKoro2ndAnniversary3DLive.
呟いてねー！
Please tweet!
嬉しいです。後で、おかゆと二人で…
We'd love that. Okayu and I will check them later...
そう。見ますからね。
Yeah. We'll be watching.
ジロジロジロジロ…いっぱい見ますから、よろしくお願いします。
Staring intently... we'll be checking them all, so please look forward to it.
えーと、上々友情は、1周年の時に…
Um, we released a cover of 'Joujou Yuujou' for our 1st anniversary...
二人で歌ったの出して、今回絶対歌いたいと思ってね。
So I definitely wanted to sing it this time.
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right, right.
一番最初に持ってきました。
We put it as the first song.
歌いたかったんで。
Because I really wanted to sing it.
良かったー！
I'm glad we did!
まずね、1曲目ちゃんと歌えたんで、安心安心。
I'm relieved we could sing the first song properly.
ね。ちょっとわちゃわちゃしたけど。
Yeah. Even if it was a bit chaotic.
そうだね。
That's true.
はい、ということであとは…
Right, and also...
そう、おにぎりゃーと、ころねすきがなんと駆けつけてくれてるってことを聞いたんだけど。
Right, I heard that the Onigiryas and Koronesukis have actually come to support us.
あ！みんなー！
Ah! Everyone!
おー！すごい！
Oh! Amazing!
あ、よかった、みんな！めっちゃいるじゃん！
Ah, I'm glad! There's so many of you!
最前列取れよ！なんか前から2、3番目くらい…
Take the front row! You're like in the 2nd or 3rd row...
そんな控えめなんだよ。最前列で頑張れよみんな！
They're so modest. Do your best to get to the front row, guys!
しかもなんか、ころねすきはペンライト持ってないのかな、これは？
And also, do the Koronesukis not have penlights?
あ、なに？ころねすきちょっとアップお願いしていいですか？
Wait, can we get a close-up of the Koronesukis?
何持ってんのそれ？何だこれは？
What are you holding? What is this?
あ！指が光ってますね！
Ah! Their fingers are glowing!
なるほどね、2周年を迎えたころねすきは指が光るようになったんだ。
I see, now that it's the 2nd anniversary, the Koronesukis' fingers have started to glow.
あ、すごいじゃん！進化だね！
That's amazing! It's an evolution!
すげー、すげー、ありがとうみんな！
Amazing, thank you everyone!
みんなありがとう来てくれて。嬉しいよ、ありがとうありがとう。
Thank you all for coming. I'm so happy, thank you, thank you.
でね、この通常衣装なんだけど…
Now, about these standard outfits...
今日はもうアイドル衣装に着替えちゃおうかなって思ってるから…
Since we're going to change into our idol costumes today...
これを見納めだから、ちょっとこれで一回スクショしてもらう？ちょっと。
This will be the last time you see these, so how about taking a screenshot now?
おー！ちょっとだけ、ちょっとだけスクショしてもらう。
Oh! Just a quick screenshot session.
おかころがこの通常衣装で並んでるのもめっちゃレアだよ。
OkaKoro standing side-by-side in these standard outfits is really rare.
みんなレア、分かってる？これレアだからね！
Everyone, do you realize how rare this is? It's rare!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
見えてる、見えてる。
I can see you, I can see you.
ワワワワワ…
Wawawawawa...
しっぽ、しっぽ見せる、しっぽ。しっぽ。
The tails, let's show our tails. Tails.
ヴイヴイヴイ…ボサボサだね。
Vui vui vui... Mine is really shaggy.
おかゆと並ぶと本当にボサボサだね。
When I stand next to Okayu, it's really shaggy.
でもそれがね、いいんだよ。
But that's what's good about it.
そう、うり、えいえいえい…
Yeah, uri, ei ei ei...
撮れた？みんな撮れた？うえーい…
Did you get it? Did everyone get the shot? Whoo...
撮れたかな？動きすぎた？
Did you get it? Did we move too much?
一回止まるか。
Let's stay still for a moment.
撮れた？撮れた？
Did you get it?
いい感じ。撮れてるはず。
Nice. I'm sure you got it.
ということでね、この後は着替えるんですけれども…
So, we're going to change after this...
あとね…もう着替えるんですけれども…
And also... we're going to change soon, but...
なんなんなんと、次の曲はおかゆのソロ曲ー！
Wait for it... the next song is Okayu's solo song!
イェーイ！大丈夫？行ける？
Yay! Are you ready? Can you do it?
できない、できない！じゃ、今日はこれで終わりにしたいと思います。
I can't, I can't! Well, I guess we'll end it here for today then.
みんなありがとうございました！バイバイ！
Thank you everyone! Bye-bye!
あれ？どういう反応が正解だった？ごめんごめん。
Wait, what was the right way to react to that? Sorry, sorry.
あ、でも頑張らなきゃだめでしょ？
Ah, but you have to do your best, right?
はい。確かに。
Yes, exactly.
行けるね！はい。
I can do it! Okay.
じゃ、あっちほら準備に行きます。
Okay, let's go get ready over there.
待っててー！
Wait for it!
はーい。
Yes!
おかゆが、えー次に歌う曲をみんな想像してみてください。
Everyone, please try to imagine the next song Okayu is going to sing.
こーねからは言いません。
Kone isn't going to tell you.
準備できた？
Are you ready?
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー！じゃあ次の曲行ってみよう！
Okay! Then let's move on to the next song!
エイリアンエイリアン
作詞・作曲 ナユタン星人
Alien Alien
Lyrics & Composition by Nayutalien
揺れる街灯 篠突く雨
Swaying streetlights, lashing rain
振れる感情 感覚のテレパス
Fluctuating emotions, a telepathy of senses
迷子の二人はコンタクト
Two lost souls make contact
心は恋を知りました
Hearts have learned what love is
タイトロープ ツギハギの制服
Tightrope, a patchwork uniform
重度のディスコミュニケーション
Severe discommunication
眼光赤色にキラキラ
Eyes sparkling in red
何かが起こる胸騒ぎ
A premonition of something about to happen
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
Bewildering your heart
混ざりあう宇宙の引力で
With the mingling gravity of the universe
感じてる気持ちはトキメキ
The feeling I'm sensing is a flutter
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
触れあえば傷は二度と消えない
If we touch, the wounds will never disappear
あなたに未体験あげる
I'll give you an experience like no other
異世界の果てまでトキメキ
A flutter that reaches the end of another world
好き
I love you
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
A fluorescent lamp flickering on and off
超常な混沌が静かにあなたを蝕んだ
Supernatural chaos has quietly consumed you
並行な信号は特異点により交わった
Parallel signals crossed at a singularity
創造現実盲信症 感応性本能
Creation-reality blind faith syndrome, sensitive instinct
シンドローム ひとりきり夜な夜な
Syndrome, all alone night after night
空想を描くまるでグリモワ
Drawing fantasies like a grimoire
地雷避ける不感症
Apathy that avoids landmines
まだあなたはすべてを知りたい？
Do you still want to know everything?
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
Bewildering your heart
瞳に映らない引力に
To a gravity invisible to the eyes
気づいてよわたしは
Notice me, I'm...
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
触れあえば傷は二度と消えない
If we touch, the wounds will never disappear
降り注ぐ無数の隕石も
Even the countless falling meteors
トキメク心には届かない
Won't reach a fluttering heart
エイリアン 二人はエイリアン
Alien, we two are aliens
高鳴る鼓動が抑えられない
I can't suppress my throbbing heart
あなたは未確認生命体
You are an unidentified lifeform
異世界の果てまであなたが
To the end of another world, you...
好き
I love you
おかゆお疲れ様ー！
Okayu, good job!
お疲れ様ー。
Good job.
踊れた？
Did you dance well?
あのさ一つ聞きたいんだけどね。
Hey, I want to ask you one thing.
なに？
What?
最後の投げキッスは誰に送ったキッスなの？
Who was that last blown kiss for?
え？
Eh?
世界中のみんなにだよ。
It was for everyone in the whole world.
待って、こーねには？
Wait, what about Kone?
チュ。
Chu.
今いただきましたので。
I've just received it.
ころさんにしか見えてないチュだよ。
It's a 'chu' that only Koro-san can see.
ありがとう。もう一回もう一回。
Thank you. One more time, one more time.
チュ。
Chu.
あ、いただきましたので大丈夫です。
Ah, I've received it, so I'm fine.
めっちゃ可愛かったね、おかゆね。
Okayu was so cute.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
すごい可愛かった。あとこーねも着替えた、どう？
So cute. And Kone also changed clothes, how do I look?
可愛いー。
You look cute.
可愛い？ありがとう。着替えました。
Cute? Thank you. I've changed.
いいね。
Nice.
はい。え、おかゆ今の曲どうだった？
Yes. So, Okayu, how was that song?
なんか踊って歌ってみてどうだった？
How did it feel to sing and dance to it?
いや「エイリアンエイリアン」はね、すごい好きな曲で。
Well, 'Alien Alien' is a song I really like.
普通になんか普段からさ、
I usually sing it, you know,
お掃除しながら歌ったりしてるけど。
while cleaning and such.
口ずさんでるよね。
You hum it, don't you?
そう、よく口ずさんでるけど、みんなの前で歌うと…
Yeah, I hum it a lot, but singing it in front of everyone...
やっぱちょっと緊張した。
I was a bit nervous after all.
緊張したよね。でも可愛かったよ。
You were nervous. But it was cute.
でも上手にできた。
But I think I did a good job.
上手にできたね、本当に。
You did a good job indeed.
エイリアン イェイイェイ。
Alien, yay yay.
可愛かった。で、次の曲もおおかゆの？
It was cute. So, is the next song Okayu's too?
んんんん…。
Hmmm...
次の曲はね、えーとおかゆのが歌ってその次に…
The next song is, well, Okayu will sing and after that...
次も歌うので、連続で聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
I'll be singing the next one too, so I'd be happy if you'd listen to them in succession.
で、おかゆ次の曲のじゃあ、ここ見てほしいポイントとかあれば。
And Okayu, is there any point you'd like people to look out for in the next song?
えっとね、次は、次もしっぽを可愛く揺らすので、
Well, next... in the next one too, I'll be swaying my tail cutely,
僕のしっぽをいっぱい見てほしい。
so I want you to look at my tail a lot.
いいねー。じゃあころねも見てるからね。
Nice. Well, Korone will be watching too.
ありがと、頑張れ。
Thanks, good luck!
じゃあころねも準備してくるぞ。
Alright, Korone's going to go get ready too.
じゃあ２曲続けてどうぞ！
Here are two songs in a row, please enjoy!
ハイ！
Hi!
彗星ハネムーン
作詞・作曲 ナユタン星人
Comet Honeymoon
Lyrics/Music: Nayutan Seijin
キラキラ光る流星群
A sparkling meteor shower
わたし想うわ、お愛に
Thinking of me, for love's sake
星の間に間に逃避行
A getaway between the stars
そんなストーリーも悪くないのさ
Such a story isn't so bad either
あぁ、お待ちなさいなプレビュー
Ah, please wait, preview
隙世・界・まで・ボン・ボヤージュ
Bon voyage to the world of love
あの星の名も忘れたの
I've forgotten the name of that star too
一つ月の光
A single moonbeam
彗星ハネムーン　あなたとランデブー
Comet Honeymoon, a rendezvous with you
恋しているのさ　たぶん
I'm in love, probably
愛してモナムール　いっそ二人きり
Love me, mon amour, just the two of us
どっか遠くへ行こうか
Shall we go somewhere far away?
曖昧なエアライン　言葉はいらない
A vague airline, no words are needed
やっと出会えたあなたと
With you, whom I've finally met
星巡り　繰り返し
Going around the stars, again and again
目指すは夢の出発星さ
Aiming for the starting star of dreams
あははーん
Ah-ha-ha-n
あははーん　もー！
Ah-ha-ha-n, jeez!
ハイ！
Hi!
初戦タイムライナー　その数回転の間
Just a time-liner, in that few rotations' span
運命線も超えた　愛のまたたきがプレイバック
Even crossed the fate line, love's twinkle plays back
感情切ないな　あなたはシューティングライナー
The feelings are painful, you're a shooting liner
ロマンス気候　今
A romance climate, now
動かない信号の赤色
The red of a traffic light that doesn't change
隙世・界・まで・お愛に
To the world of love, for our meeting
星屑の海が旅の終わり
The sea of stardust is the end of the journey
そこで お別れさ
And there, we say goodbye
彗星ハネムーン　あなたとランデブー
Comet Honeymoon, a rendezvous with you
恋しているのさ　二人
We're in love, the two of us
愛してモナムール　理由なんてなくても
Love me, mon amour, even without a reason
いいよ遠くへ行こうか
It's okay, shall we go far away?
彗星ハネムーン　果てまでランデブー
Comet Honeymoon, a rendezvous to the end
そうさ今だけは二人
That's right, just for now, it's the two of us
ねぇ聞いてモナムール　片道切符でも
Hey listen, mon amour, even with a one-way ticket
いいですよ
It's alright
夜が明けたら　どこへ行こうか
When night breaks, where shall we go?
永遠に出会えぬあなたと
With you, whom I'll never meet for real
星巡り　繰り返し
Going around the stars, again and again
目指すは夢の出発星さ
Aiming for the starting star of dreams
あははーん
Ah-ha-ha-n
あははーん　もー！
Ah-ha-ha-n, jeez!
ハイ！
Hi!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging me
おねがいダーリン
作詞・作曲 ナナホシ管弦楽団
Please Darling
Lyrics/Music: Nanahoshi Orchestra
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you never listen to what I say at all
あれほどやめてって言ったタバコもやめない
You won't even quit the cigarettes I told you to stop
泣きつく前に手洗って7回 1, 2, ...
Wash your hands seven times before crying to me. 1, 2, ...
...ともかく欠かさず 感動やられて
...Anyway, don't miss a single one. Getting emotional,
お節介になっても看病してあげないんだから!
Even if I get nosy, I'm not going to nurse you!
あいや、降参って言葉も出ない? あなたのハートは真っ黒です!
Oh, not even a word of surrender? Your heart is pitch black!
言いたいことは言わないし 聞きたいことなら聞かないし
You won't say what you want to say, and you won't listen to what I want to ask.
最初からやりたいことまで 決まってるすべて飲まないし
You won't accept everything from the start to what you want to do.
ねえ そんなのバカみたいじゃない?
Hey, isn't that just stupid?
そうじゃない じゃない じゃない じゃない...
It's not that, not that, not that, not that...
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
Always with that suggestive air,
察してほしい感じで
with that "I want you to figure it out" vibe,
わざと口にしないの
intentionally not saying a word.
ずるくない?
Isn't that unfair?
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて ほしいのは形のないもの
Please, darling! Look and listen, what I want is something formless.
バカにしないで 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me! Look and listen, look deep into my eyes.
まっすぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Stare straight at me, I want you to try begging me.
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに今ではすっかりしらんぷり
Even though I've gazed at you so devotedly, now you're completely ignoring me.
っていうかそれって自惚れなんじゃないですか? ぶっちゃけ
I mean, isn't that just conceit? Honestly.
さっさと参った! あなたのおかげで私のハートはボロボロです!
Hurry up and surrender! Thanks to you, my heart is in tatters!
連れないときは連れないし ソッチがなかなか言い出さないから
When you're cold, you're cold, and since you won't come out and say it,
いつも私が舵取り
I'm always the one steering.
ねえ なんだかバカみたいじゃない?
Hey, doesn't it feel kind of stupid?
そうじゃない じゃない じゃない じゃない...
It's not that, not that, not that, not that...
どこか足元見てる感じで
Like you're looking down on me somehow,
値踏みされてる感じで
like I'm being appraised,
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃなくない?
it's not about tactics or winning and losing, is it?
そういう面倒くさいことしてるから面倒くさいことになるんだよ!
Doing those troublesome things is why it becomes troublesome!
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent darling! Don't sleep on me, this sadness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away! Don't run away! Touch the depths of my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない おねだりしてはくれないの?
It's not just for a moment, won't you beg me?
言葉にできない臆病者は 賢かさではないのよ
Being too cowardly to speak isn't the same as being clever.
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Don't be spoiled, just say it!
もう、ちゃんとこっち向いてったら!
Jeez, I said look this way!
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて ほしいのは形のないもの
Please, darling! Look and listen, what I want is something formless.
バカにしないで 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me! Look and listen, look deep into my eyes.
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで 暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Silent darling! Don't sleep on me, reveal my true face.
お願いダーリン そばにいて 触らせて 心の奥の方
Please, darling! Stay by my side, let me touch the depths of your heart.
まっすぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Stare straight at me, I want you to try begging me.
お願いダーリン
Please, darling.
うわあああ!
Waaaah!
転んじゃった...
I fell down...
最後転んじゃった。
I fell down at the very end.
大丈夫? 大大丈夫? ちょっと。
Are you okay? Are you okay? Good grief.
よろけちゃった...
I stumbled...
よろけてしまって... 大丈夫だとバレてない? バレてない?
I stumbled... Did they notice? Did they?
バレてない。
They didn't notice.
あ、見てなかったから。
Oh, I wasn't looking.
慌てて来て、奇跡的に見てなかった。
I came in a hurry, and miraculously I didn't see it.
本当に!?
Really!?
いや、めっちゃすごかった、ダンス。
No, the dance was amazing.
いや、もう最後で、もう全部吹き飛んだんだけど。
I mean, that ending just blew everything else away.
いや、でも、ころさんね、ずっとね、このダンス練習してたから。
But Korone, you've been practicing this dance for a long time.
練習してた...
I was practicing...
そう、でも最後転んじゃったけど、あともう完璧だったじゃん。
Yeah, you fell at the end, but everything else was perfect.
ね。
Right?
はい...
Yes...
でも、みんなさ、すごいね。コメントでも、僕、見てたんだけど。
But everyone was amazing. I was looking at the comments.
本当?
Really?
すごいなんか「圧が気持ちいい」みたいな。
They were saying things like "The pressure feels good."
「可愛い、可愛い」ってね、みんな言ってたよ。
Everyone was saying "Cute, cute."
えへへ、ありがとう。
Hehe, thank you.
おかゆも見てくれてありがとう。
Thank you for watching too, Okayu.
応援してた、ばっちり。
I was rooting for you, perfectly.
ばっちり応援してた。
Rooting for you all the way.
やばい、今度は転ばないようにしなきゃ。
Oh no, I have to make sure I don't fall next time.
え、次のさ、曲はさ、その、何をさ、注目して見てみたらいいの?
So, what should we look out for in the next song?
次の曲は、結構、えっとね、なんかテンポが速いというか、ノリノリな曲だから。
The next song has a pretty fast tempo and is really upbeat.
ちょっとそれに合わせて、ころねが頑張って動いてるところをね、
So I want you to watch me working hard to keep up with the rhythm.
見てほしいけど、
But...
また転ぶかもしれないから、そこに注目してください。
I might fall again, so please keep an eye out for that.
だってよ、みんな。ころさんがね、
You heard her, everyone. Korone says...
もしかしたら転ぶかもしれないけど、転ばないかもしれないっていうのを、ちょっと楽しんでね。
...to enjoy the suspense of whether she'll fall or not.
楽しんでください。
Please enjoy it.
よし、見ていけたらなって思いますね。
Alright, let's see how it goes.
はい。
Okay.
ころさん、大丈夫? ちょっと、あの、休憩する? お水飲んで、お水。
Korone, are you okay? Do you want to take a break? Drink some water.
や、マジで。おかゆの、あの、「頑張ってころさん」っていうね、
No, really. If I can get a "Good luck, Korone-san" from you,
あの、可愛いポーズと、キメ顔もらえたら、ころね頑張れるから。
with a cute pose and a cool face, I can do my best.
あ、でもさっきの「お願いダーリン」みたいに。
Ah, just like in "Onegai Darling" just now.
あ、ちょっと僕も、振り向いて、やろうかな。
Maybe I should turn around and do it too.
いいね、いいね! じゃあ、お願いしていいですか?
Nice, nice! Then, could you do it for me?
はい。
Sure.
じゃあ振り向いて。
Turning around now.
こっちから。
From this side.
ころさん、頑張って!
Korone-san, do your best!
頑張る!
I'll do my best!
行ってみよう!
Let's go!
ということで、では、ころさんの次の曲、どうぞ!
And with that, here's Korone-san's next song. Please!
ダメダメよ！
No way, no way!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
作詞・作曲：samfree
Luka Luka Night Fever
Lyrics/Composition: samfree
右から左へと 言葉が流れる
Words flow from right to left
退屈そうな顔 画面見つめる君
You stare at the screen with a bored expression
次元の壁越えて いつでも会いに行く
I'll cross the dimensional wall to see you anytime
心の準備を ちゃんとしておいてね
Please make sure your heart is prepared
君のこと誰よりもわかってる だから私に任せて
I understand you better than anyone else, so leave it to me
怖がらないで 二人で踊りましょう
Don't be afraid, let's dance together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー はじけるリズムに合わせて
Luka Luka Night Fever, to the bursting rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも 全部忘れて
Forget every single unpleasant thing
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 私はここにいるから
Luka Luka Night Fever, because I am right here
少しでも視線を そらしちゃダメダメよ
Don't you dare look away, even for a second
重くて見れない日 アニキに釣られた日
On days it's too heavy to watch, or when you're lured by 'Aniki'
心で呼んでみて すぐに飛んで行くわ
Try calling me in your heart, I'll fly to you immediately
授業では教わらないことを 君に教えてあげるわ
I'll teach you things you won't learn in class
夜の扉を 二人で開きましょう
Let's open the door to the night together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー あふれる想いを付与（ふよ）
Luka Luka Night Fever, granting you these overflowing feelings
限りあるこの時を 胸に刻んで
Etch this limited time into your heart
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 朝日が昇ればサヨナラ
Luka Luka Night Fever, it's goodbye when the sun rises
寂しそうなその目 されてもダメダメよ
Even if you give me those lonely eyes, it's no good
君のこと誰よりもわかってる だからすべてをさらして
I understand you better than anyone else, so reveal everything
生まれた意味を 二人で見つけましょう
Let's find the meaning of our birth together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 高まる鼓動を感じて
Luka Luka Night Fever, feel your rising heartbeat
さあ覚悟できたら この手をとって
Now, if you're ready, take my hand
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 輝く君が好きーなの
Luka Luka Night Fever, I love the shining you
全力で飛び出そう 用意はいいかしら
Let's jump out with all our might, are you ready?
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー はじけるリズムに合わせて
Luka Luka Night Fever, to the bursting rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも 全部忘れて
Forget every single unpleasant thing
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 私はここにいるから
Luka Luka Night Fever, because I am right here
少しでも視線を そらしちゃダメダメよ
Don't you dare look away, even for a second
ダメダメよ！
No way, no way!
お疲れー！
Great job!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
いや、めっちゃすごかった！
Wow, that was truly amazing!
ありがとう、おかゆ！みんなもありがとう！
Thank you, Okayu! And thank you everyone too!
いやもうなんかさ、ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバーさ、僕めっちゃ好きなのね、この曲。
I mean, you know, I really love this song, 'Luka Luka Night Fever'.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
それで、そう、ころさんダンス上手いし、声がさ可愛いからすごい似合っててね、良かったよ！
And yeah, Korone-san's dancing is great and your voice is so cute, it really suited you! It was great!
あー嬉しい！嬉しい！
Ah, I'm so happy! So happy!
おかゆも可愛かったよ！ね、みんなね！
Okayu was cute too! Right, everyone?
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm happy!
あれ好き、「タラッタラッタラッ」のところ。
I love that part, the 'ta-ra-ta-ra-ta' part.
ららららら～ 響け、あなたに！
La la la la la~ reach you!
大好きだった
I loved you.
いぇーい！
Yay!
みんなの気持ちをね、こう、ね、代弁してね
I'm speaking on behalf of everyone's feelings.
かわいいよー！かわいいよー！
You're so cute! You're so cute!
僕はね、あれだから。うん、うん。ころさんはやっぱ、うーんってなってた
As for me... yeah. Korone-san was like, 'Mmm,' after all.
本当にありがとう！保護者だね、もう
Thank you so much! You're like a guardian now.
そう、もうね、うん、うん。さすがだね、分かってたけどね、みたいな
Right, exactly. As expected, I knew it, though.
ありがとね
Thanks.
で、こん、えっと、今の時間はね、えっと、
So, now... well, at this time...
このアイドル衣装でおかころってなかなかね、二人で配信することないから
the two of us rarely stream together as OkaKoro in these idol outfits,
確かに
True.
本当に。ちょっと待って
Really. Wait a sec.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
今更ちょっと疲れがきた
I'm starting to feel the fatigue now.
大丈夫だよ。じゃあ、僕が代わりに
It's okay. I'll take over.
この衣装で、まぁ、二人で並ぶ事ってすごい珍しいので、
Since it's very rare for the two of us to stand side-by-side in these outfits,
今回は、えっと、少しの時間、おかころの写真撮影をしていこうかなと思います
I think we'll do an OkaKoro photo shoot for a bit.
いぇーい！やったー！
Yay! Hurray!
なんかね、コメントにね、どんなポーズが欲しいかとかね、色々ね
Like, let us know in the comments what kind of poses you want.
そうだね、教えてもらえれば... 教えてもらいつつ...
Yeah, if you could tell us... while taking suggestions...
そうだね、それにお答えしていこうかなって。フォトタイムということで
Right, we'll try to do those. It's photo time.
スクショタイムということで、みんなこの上のタグをさ、つけてさ、
Since it's screenshot time, if everyone used the tag up there,
あの投稿してくれたらすごい嬉しいよ
and posted them, I'd be really happy.
嬉しいよ
We'd be happy.
ありがとう
Thank you.
あ、カメラある、カメラある
Ah, there's a camera, there's a camera.
わーわーわー
Wah wah wah!
いいね、いいね。どんなポーズがいいかな？
Nice, nice. What kind of pose should we do?
あ、ハートマーク作る？ハートマーク
Oh, should we make a heart mark? A heart mark.
そうだね、いいよ。じゃあ、手で作ろう、手で。よくいるやつ
Right, okay. Let's make it with our hands. The usual one.
いいよ
Okay.
ハートじゃない... あ、ごめんごめんごめん
That's not a heart... Ah, sorry, sorry, sorry.
ハート！
Heart!
ハートじゃない...
That's not a heart...
ごめんごめんごめん
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
うわぁー！
Waaaah!
うぇーい！ごめん、ごめんごめん
Wheee! Sorry, sorry, sorry.
もう。ごめん、すぐチューするんですけど
Geez. Sorry, she keeps trying to kiss me.
いいでしょ
It's fine, right?
今日だけだから。ハート、これなら、大きいハートなら作れるんじゃない？
Since it's only for today. Maybe we can make a big heart like this?
大きいハート。よし、いこう
A big heart. Alright, let's go.
どう？いいだろ
How's this? Good, right?
あ、待って、スクエアならいけるっしょ
Oh, wait, we can do a square, right?
あ、いけた、いけた。四角。四角
Ah, we did it, we did it. A square. A square.
これじゃダメかな？
Is this no good?
どうだろう。でも、みんな可愛いとは言ってくれてるけど
I wonder. But everyone's saying it's cute.
え、お尻も撮ってもらう？お尻も
Should we let them take a photo of our butts? Butts too.
お尻撮ってもらう。はいよー。しっぽ。アイドルしっぽです
Let them take a photo of our butts. Okay. Tails. These are idol tails.
あぁ、アイドルしっぽです
Ah, these are idol tails.
なんか、おかゆのしっぽと並ぶと本当にころねのしっぽさ、
When lined up with Okayu's tail, doesn't Korone's tail look
立派じゃないかな？
really magnificent?
いや、それが可愛いんだよ。立派じゃん、立派
No, that's what makes it cute. It's magnificent, magnificent.
ありがとう。ちょっとやそっとのことじゃ千切れないからね
Thank you. It won't tear easily, you know.
確かに僕のすぐ千切れちゃうからね
True, mine tears easily.
ちょっと分けてあげるから
I'll give you a bit of mine.
いらない。いらない
I don't need it. I don't need it.
取れたかなみんな？取れた？
Did you get it, everyone? Did you get it?
やっぱ、僕たちはしっぽが可愛いからね、しっぽがね
After all, our tails are cute, aren't they?
そうだね。なんかコメントで、みんな良いよって言っていいんだよ、もっと
Right. People in the comments, it's okay to say it's good, more.
自分をさらけ出して。どんな、どんなポーズがいいとか、本当にレアだからね
Expose yourselves. Like what kind of pose you want... this is really rare.
みんな分かってるこれ？
Do you all understand that?
いや、多分ね、ころね自身がね、おかゆとのね、あの、メモリーを残したいんだよ、きっと
No, probably Korone herself wants to leave memories with Okayu, surely.
そう、だからみんななんか。メモリーをね。そうだね。なんか
So, everyone, please... Memories, yeah. Right. Something...
抱き合って、だって
They said 'Hugging'.
あー。抱き合ってる。そうだね。ぎゅー、ぎゅー。
Ah, hugging. Right. Hug, hug.
ぎゅーぎゅー
Huggy huggy.
取れた？
Did you get it?
ハイタッチして、だって
They said 'High touch'.
いぇーい！
Yay!
あ、これ取れなくない？
Ah, isn't this hard to capture?
確かに. みんなスローで、スローモーションで。スローモーションで
True. Everyone, do it in slow motion. Slow motion.
いぇーーい！
Yaaaaay!
取れた？
Did you get it?
これなら。これなら取れるんじゃない？
With this... with this, you can probably get it, right?
楽しいな
This is fun.
ね、すごい楽しい
Yeah, it's really fun.
ジャンプして、ジャンプして
Jump, jump!
わー。あ、一人で
Wah! Ah, just one of us.
二人で。二人でジャンプする？
Both together. Should we jump together?
せーの、うぇーい！
Ready, go! Wheee!
でもなんかスカートめくれちゃうこれ
But like, our skirts might flip up.
あ、ダメだ、これダメだ。ダメだ。スカートめくれてしまうね
Ah, no, this is bad. Our skirts will flip up.
あと何だ？あ、あのさ、初めてのさ、おかころ3Dコラボ覚えてる？
What else? Ah, you know, do you remember our very first OkaKoro 3D collab?
フュージョンやったじゃん。あ、やった
We did 'Fusion'. Ah, we did.
やってもいいかな？
Can we do it?
フューー... ジョン！ハッ！
Fu... sion! Ha!
あー。あー。あー、失敗した
Ah... ah... ah, we failed.
失敗したわ
We failed.
失敗したわ。ダメだね
We failed. No good.
しばきあげパンチングだって。やってみて。カメラに近づいて
They said 'Shibaki-age punching'. Try it. Get close to the camera.
ほらよ！そんな感じなの？あ、どう、あ、普通にもっと
Take that! Is it like that? Ah, how about... ah, just more normally...
ほらよ！
Take that!
デンプシーロール
Dempsey Roll!
うぉー！うぉー！うぉー！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
あ、観客も交えて撮影しない？
Ah, should we take a photo with the audience too?
あ、そうだね。オニキスとおにぎりゃー
Ah, right. Onyx and Onigirya.
こっち、こっち。よくさ、こうやって、こういうのやりたい、こういうの
This way, this way. You know, I want to do this kind of thing.
確かに. すごい、いいじゃん！
True. Wow, that's great!
あ、いいじゃん！はぁー
Ah, it's good! Haaah.
いや、なんで最前取れなかったんマジで。カメラマン、カモンカモン
Wait, why couldn't you guys take the front row, seriously? Cameraman, come on!
カモンカモン。カモンカモン
Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
最前入れよ
Get to the front!
確かに. ギリギリ前取れてない感じだ
True. Feels like we can't quite get to the very front.
いぇーい。ピース、ピース。ピース。どう？取れたみんな？
Yay. Peace, peace. Peace. How's that? Did you get it, everyone?
いいじゃん。いいじゃん。ね、いいよね。はーい
It's good. It's good. Yeah, it's nice. Okay.
可愛い
Cute.
いいね
Nice.
いいですね
It is nice.
いい感じ？
Is it looking good?
あ、ごめんよだって
Oh, they're saying "Sorry."
最前取れなくてごめんよ謝っとる
They're apologizing for not being able to get the front row.
ダメだったんだね
They couldn't get it, huh.
ま、確かに一番前取るのってめっちゃ難しいからね
Well, it's definitely really hard to get the very front row.
確かに
True.
あー、なんかすごさ、なんか緊張とさ、なんか踊った疲れとさ
Ah, it's like, the nervousness and the exhaustion from dancing...
まぁ、ころさん2連続ね激しめのダンスだったからね
Well, Koro-san had two intense dances in a row.
煽いであげる
I'll fan you.
ありがとう
Thank you.
あー！
Ah!
あー、飛ばされていく
Ah, I'm being blown away!
あー！
Ah!
飛ばされてっちゃった
I got blown away.
楽しい、楽しい、楽しい
Fun, fun, fun!
犬と猫のポーズとかやってみる？
Want to try doing dog and cat poses?
いいよ
Sure.
じゃあ、犬のポーズって何だ？
Well, what's a dog pose?
お散歩
Go for a walk.
ワン、ワン、ワン
Woof, woof, woof.
ほら行くよ
Come on, let's go.
ワン、ワン
Woof, woof.
こっちだよ
This way.
ワン、ワン
Woof, woof.
こっちだよ
This way.
膝が、膝が割れる！
My knees, my knees are gonna break!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ありがとう
Thank you.
猫のポーズ、猫のポーズ
Cat pose, cat pose.
ニャン、ニャン、ニャン
Meow, meow, meow.
今の何だったん、今の
What was that just now?
ニャン、ニャン、ニャン
Meow, meow, meow.
おかゆのアップちょうだい
Give us a close-up of Okayu.
ニャン、ニャン、ニャン
Meow, meow, meow.
可愛い、可愛いでちゅね
Cute, so cute.
さっきの何だったんだ
What was that earlier?
待って、おかゆも犬のポーズ
Wait, Okayu, do the dog pose too.
えぇー、膝疲れるじゃん
Eh, it'll tire out my knees.
ほら、お散歩
Come on, for a walk.
おいいで、おいで
Come here, come here.
動けない
I can't move.
おいで、おいで
Come here, come here.
やだ、やだ
No, no way.
リード長すぎだろ、これ
The leash is too long!
ダメだ、この猫ちゃんはダメだ、言うこと聞かない
It's no good, this kitty is no good, she won't listen.
そうだね
That's right.
一筋縄ではいかないんだ
She's not easily handled.
くそぉ
Darn it.
ダンスより今のこれで、すごい疲れたんだ
I'm more tired from this than from the dancing.
リードで、リードですごい疲れた
The leash, the leash really tired me out.
何を見せられてるんだってコメント、あ、すみませんでした
"What am I watching?" says the comment. Oh, sorry about that.
申し訳ない
Our apologies.
あとは、なんかみんなある？なんか本当今日控えめだね、なんで？
Anything else from everyone? You guys are really quiet today, why?
みんなも緊張してるんじゃない？
Aren't they nervous too?
久しぶりのさ、おかころライブで
Since it's an Okakoro live after such a long time.
大乱闘しあって
Let's rumble.
ほら、乱舞して
Come on, dance wildly.
お背中合わせやってだって
They're asking us to stand back-to-back.
あ、こういうこと？
Ah, like this?
かっこいい
Cool.
あ、次の曲っぽくない？あ、言っちゃった、あ、言っちゃった
Ah, doesn't this feel like the next song? Ah, I said it, I said it.
何？次の曲っぽいって
What do you mean, "feels like the next song"?
バレてない、バレてない、バレてない
It didn't slip, it didn't slip, it didn't slip.
ネタバレころさんだ、ネタバレ犬だ
It's Spoiler Korosan, Spoiler Dog.
あ、えー、じゃあ次の曲、何だと思う？みんな
So, uh, what do you think the next song is, everyone?
予想
Guess.
これっぽいだって
They're saying "like this."
あれ？できんくなった
Huh? I can't do it anymore.
あー、とか言ってるけど、みんな分かってないなこれ
They're saying "ah," but no one gets it.
そんなに当たってないよ、みんな
You guys aren't even close.
残念でした
Too bad.
じゃあ、みんなも気になってるだろうし、そろそろ言ってみる？
Well, since everyone's curious, shall we say it soon?
行きますか？
Shall we go?
じゃあ、早速次の曲に行きたいと思います！
Well then, let's head straight to the next song!
せーの...
Ready...
ロ、キ、ラー！
Ro-ki-ra!
ロキ
Roki
作詞・作曲・みきとP
Lyrics/Composition by Mikito-P
さあ、独壇場
Now, it's our stage.
終夜灯 30ワット
All-night lamp, 30 watts.
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが
Subculture boy with a Telecaster on his back...
バンドの仲間にヤッホー
...says "Yo" to his bandmates.
アルバイト根暗モード
Part-time job, gloomy mode.
対バンにはATフィールド
AT Field against opposing bands.
人見知り宣言で逃げるキッカケ
Escaping with a declaration of shyness...
ボーイ
...boy.
言うて お坊ちゃん お嬢ちゃん
Having said that, young masters and ladies,
お金も 才能も
money and talent,
なまじあるだけ厄介でやんす
having just a bit of them is just bothersome.
Boys be ambitious
Like this old man
長い前髪 君 誰の信者
With your long bangs, whose follower are you?
死んじゃう
I'm gonna die.
勘違いすんな　教祖はお前だ
Don't get me wrong, you're the cult leader.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは　Don’t Stop!　Don’t Stop!
The strumming electric guitar, Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ　君のすべてを
Now, everything about you...
曝け出してみせろよ
...expose it all.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
さあ　一進一退
Come on, back and forth.
いい曲書いてる？
Are you writing good songs?
余裕こいてる？
Are you taking it easy?
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないかな
You're well-known but not so popular,
いろいろ大変ですね
it must be tough.
はっきり言えよ匿名アイコン
Just say it, anonymous icon.
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
A real-life icon that doesn't show clearly.
いい年こいて自意識まだBOY
At that age, still self-conscious like a BOY.
ぶっちゃけ　どんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
To be honest, no matter how smart or calculated you act,
10年後にマイクは落ちてんだよ
in ten years, you'll have dropped the mic.
BOYISH
RADIOMEN
生き抜くためにお抱きメロ　テカ　Selfie
Hold onto a melody to survive, take a Selfie.
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you dare die, for both our sakes.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
薄っぺらいラブソングでも　Don’t Stop!　Don’t Stop!
Even if it's a shallow love song, Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ　目の前のあの子を
Now, that girl in front of you...
撃ち抜いてみせろよ
...go ahead and shoot her through.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
I can't be satisfied by beating around the bush.
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコートは
The Throat Coat brought to the studio...
安心はシンプルなプレッシャーでいっぱい
...peace of mind is full of simple pressure.
実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません
Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and lost my voice.
は？
Huh?
はーー！
Haaaaah!
はぁ...
Haaah...
寝言は寝て言え
Save the sleep-talking for when you're asleep.
BABY
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you dare die, for both our sakes.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは　Don’t Stop!　Don’t Stop!
The strumming electric guitar, Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ　君のすべてを
Now, everything about you...
曝け出してみせろよ
...expose it all.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
ROKI ROKI Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll.
ロキロキの
ROKI ROKI...
ロックンロール
...Rock 'n' Roll.
ロキロキの
ROKI ROKI...
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you dare die!
死にたかねーのはお互い様
Neither of us wants to die.
いやー、よかったよ！
Man, that was great!
ロキ！
ROKI!
もうぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょんしすぎたね。
We were jumping around way too much.
ぴょんぴょんしすぎたね。
We really were.
あ、みんなもパチパチありがとう！
Oh, and thank you for the applause, everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ちょっと激しめだったね。
That was a bit intense.
そうだね。
It was.
え、どうだったころさんはさ、ロキを踊ってみて、
So, how was it for you, Korone-san, dancing to ROKI?
ここちょっと注目してほしいなみたいな。
Is there anything you want us to pay attention to?
注目か。でもね、なにか、この立ち位置を変わるときあったでな。
Attention, huh. Well, there was that part where we swapped positions.
あ、入れ替わるときね。
Oh, when we switched places.
あれすごいさ、なんか本当コンビって感じでよかったと思わん？
That part was great, it really felt like we were a duo, don't you think?
みんなちょっと。あとあれだでな。
Everyone. And then there was that other thing.
うん。
Yeah.
僕ね、あの受け身取ったりするの超上手いから。
I'm actually super good at taking falls and stuff.
上手いよね。安心して殴れる。
You are. I can hit you without worrying.
殴られ慣れてるみたいなこと言うなよ。
Don't make it sound like I'm used to being hit.
気持ちよかった気持ちよかった。
It felt good, it felt good.
ちょっと問題発言ですけどそれ。大丈夫だった？
That's a bit of a problematic statement. Were you okay?
大丈夫大丈夫。なぜなら…
I'm fine, I'm fine. Because...
よしよし。
There, there.
痛い！
Ouch!
何でだよ！怪力だなぁころ。
What the heck! You're so strong, Koro.
何も触ってねーじゃん。
You didn't even touch me.
わしわしわし。
Washi washi washi.
みんな、みんなありがとうね。
Thank you, everyone.
よかったよかった。
That was great.
もう草しか生えない、草しか生えない。
I can't stop laughing, lol lol lol.
え、もうさ、ぶっちゃけね、ちょっと話変わっちゃうけど、
Anyway, to be honest, changing the subject a bit...
まここでさ、ま今まで2周年、
...it's been two years now...
ここまで色んなことあったけどさ、どうだったころさん？
...a lot has happened. How do you feel about it, Korone-san?
や、でもやっぱりさ、なんだろう…
Well, I mean, how should I put it...
なんだろう？
How should you put it?
えもさ、本当エイプリルフールに発表だったじゃん。
Well, we were actually announced on April Fools' Day.
うん、そうだね。
Yeah, that's right.
やみんながさ、なんか「え、嘘じゃーん」みたいな。
And everyone was like, "Wait, is this a joke?"
ま嘘だね。「本当なの？嘘なの？どっち？」みたいな流れだったじゃん。
Yeah, "Is it real? Is it a lie? Which is it?" That was the vibe.
だからちょっとデビューしづらかったよね。
So it was kind of hard to debut, you know?
ま確かに。でも僕もニヤニヤしてたけど。
True. But I was grinning about it too.
本当に？好きだもんねそういうの。
Really? You do love stuff like that.
ちっちっち、本当なんだけどなーって。
Hehe, I was thinking, "It's actually true though!"
ね。でもさ、えーと、おかころがデビューしてからね、
Right. But since Okakoro debuted...
結構本当今仲間がいっぱい増えたじゃんか。
...we've really gained so many friends now.
ま、僕たちがさ、その今ね、たくさんいるけどメンバー、その中で…
Yeah, there are so many members now, and among them...
だからたぶん真ん中あたりが、ちょうど僕たちみたいな感じなのかな。
So I guess the middle part is just about like us.
確かにそうだね。
That's true.
ね！今いっぱい仲間がいて本当にね、あの、いっぱい。
Right! We have so many friends now, really, like, so many.
いや本当に賑やかになったよね。
Yeah, it's really gotten lively, hasn't it?
そうだね、本当に。
It really has.
ありがとう。本当にみんなのおかげだよ。応援してくれるみんながいるから。
Thank you. It's all thanks to everyone. It's because you all support us.
うん、もちろん。
Yeah, of course.
いっぱい、あ、これからも楽しく活動ができます。本当にありがとうございます。
We can keep... we can keep doing our activities happily. Thank you so much.
ありがとうございまーす。嬉しいね。
Thank you very much. I'm so happy.
しかもね、やっぱ僕たち、途中からゲーマーズに2人で入るってなったんだけど、
And you know, we both joined Gamers together partway through,
そん時にね、ころさんに僕からその「ホロライブ一緒に歌おうよ」って、
and back then, I was the one who asked Koro-san, "Let's join Hololive together!"
「面白そうだから入ろうよ」ってさ。
"It looks fun, so let's join!"
うん、おかゆがね、声かけてくれて。こーねはちょっと「あ、あ、行ってみようかな」みたいな。
Yeah, Okayu reached out to me. And Ko-ne was like, "Oh, maybe I should try it out."
そうそうそう。それでね、まあこうやって今なんだかんだ2周年を迎えられてるっていうのが僕はすごくね、
Right, right. And being able to reach our 2nd anniversary like this together,
ありがたくも嬉しいような、そんな気がしているんだよね。
I feel both grateful and happy about it.
ね、来年も一緒にこうやってね、お互い並んで、3周年もね、迎えたいと思いますので。
Yeah, I want us to stand side-by-side like this next year too, and reach our 3rd anniversary.
そうだね、ずっと一緒にいたいね。
Yeah, I want to be with you forever.
ね、おかゆとも一緒にいっぱいいたいし、みんなともね、もちろん、ずっと一緒にいたいので。
Yeah, I want to be with Okayu a lot, and of course with everyone too, I want to be with you all forever.
そうだね。よろしくね。
Yeah. Take care of us.
ここでね、くるって回転して、あれ。観客映したらすごいエモいこと。
Let's spin around here and... show the audience, it'll be so moving.
あ！あー！どうもどうも。
Ah! Ah! Hello, hello!
ちょっといいんじゃない？ありがとうみんな！
That was pretty good, wasn't it? Thank you everyone!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いい感じだった今。
That felt great just now.
そうだね。ちょっとエモ...エモチックパートでしたね。
Yeah. That was a bit of an "emotional" part.
よかった。
That was good.
さあ、それでね、今回のライブはこの歌がね、次の歌が最後になっちゃうんですよ、実は。
Now then, for this live, this song... actually, the next song will be the last one.
やだ！
No way!
やだね。
It's sad.
やだ！やだやだやだ！
No! No no no!
待ってちょっと早すぎんか？ちょっと待ってよ。やだやだ。
Wait, isn't it a bit too early? Wait a minute. No way.
あと1時間2時間。OKですって。
Another one or two hours... they're saying "OK".
あと1時間2時間。
Another one or two hours.
OKですって言ってるよ。OKですって言ってる。
They're saying it's OK. They're saying it's OK.
社交辞令ですか？
Is that just lip service?
あ、そうですって言ってるよ。
Ah, they're saying "Yes, it is".
嘘！
No!
そうだよ。それをね、鵜呑みにして大人になっちゃダメなんだよ。
That's right. You can't take that literally if you want to be a grown-up.
ああ、そういう勉強会ということで、今日は。
Oh, so today is a learning session, then.
そうだよ。「はい」という名の「いいえ」なんだよ、こういうのはね。
Exactly. In cases like this, "Yes" actually means "No".
分かった。えー寂しい。みんなも寂しいよね。
I see. Man, I'm sad. Everyone's sad too, right?
僕もさ、寂しいんだよ、本当は。
I'm actually sad too, to be honest.
本当に？おかゆは強い子だ。
Really? Okayu is a strong girl.
あ、エモい、エモい。
Ah, so emotional, so emotional.
あ、待って。もうスクショいらん？大丈夫みんな？
Ah, wait. Are you guys done with screenshots? Is everyone okay?
大丈夫？時間ちょっとあるで。
Are you okay? We still have a little time.
うぇーい。
Yay!
時間ちょっとあるで。
We still have a little time.
ういー。
Woo!
カメラマンさん、カメラマンさん！あ、おかゆ。
Mr. Cameraman, Mr. Cameraman! Oh, Okayu.
わー。
Wah!
必死の。
Such a desperate...
1、2分ちょっとさ、やっぱりまたスクショタイムで最後バイバイしたいよ。早い！1時間って早いわ！何でこんな早いんだろうね。
For the last minute or two, I want to say goodbye with one last screenshot time. It's so fast! One hour goes by so fast! Why is it so fast?
切なーってやつです。
It's what you call "fleeting".
切な死だよ。
It's "fleeting death".
早いんだよ。時間って。
Time really flies.
何？運転してほしい？いいよ。ぶぉーん。
What? You want me to drive? Okay. Vroom!
何してんねん。
What am I even doing?
いや、ころさんの車が見えるメガネ。
No, these are glasses that let me see Koro-san's car.
待って。こーねが運転しておかゆ迎えに来るからさ。乗って。
Wait. Ko-ne will drive and come pick you up, Okayu. Get in.
分かった。分かった。ぶぉーん。
Okay, okay. Vroom!
あ、ころさん！
Ah, Koro-san!
やほー。乗っていいな。
Yahoo! You can get in.
いいよ。ぶぉーん。
Okay. Vroom!
ぶぉーん。
Vroom!
楽しいこれ。
This is fun.
待って、それ楽しい？楽しかった？
Wait, is that fun? Was it fun?
僕たちは楽しいけどね。
We're having fun, at least.
楽しくない？大丈夫？
Is it not fun? Are you guys okay?
バイクもいい、バイク。
A bike is good too, a bike.
あ、バイク、いいよ、いいよ。じゃあまた迎えに来てもらおうかな。
Oh, a bike? Okay, okay. Then I'll have you come pick me up again.
ええよ。ぶぉーん。きー！
Sure thing. Vroom! Screech!
あ、ころさん！
Ah, Koro-san!
おかゆ、乗りな。
Okayu, hop on.
あ、ちょっと待って。おらヘルメット。
Oh, wait. Here's your helmet.
ぶぉーん。
Vroom!
楽しいのこれ？全然楽しくないよね。
Is this fun? It's not fun at all, is it?
やっじまった。やっちまった、ちょっとシュールな。
I messed up. I messed up, this is a bit surreal.
シュールなね。
Surreal, yeah.
やばいな。笑いを提供してしまいましたけれど。
This is bad. We ended up providing some laughs.
じゃあ踊る？
Shall we dance then?
そうだよ。もう踊らないとだよ。
Yeah. We really have to dance now.
そうだね。ちょっとトークの時間短くなっちゃうけど、次の曲ね、頑張って歌って踊るので。
You're right. Our talk time is getting short, but we'll do our best to sing and dance the next song.
おかゆどう？次の曲。ポイントじゃあ。
What about you, Okayu? For the next song. Give us a highlight.
ポイントは、僕ところさんは、もしかしたら別の動きをするかもしれない。
The highlight is... me and Koro-san might do different moves.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
そう。そんな気がしてならないんだよね。
Yeah. I can't help but feel that way.
本当に？ポイント。
Really? A highlight.
なんかそんな気がするんだよ。
I just have a feeling.
分かった。じゃあ頑張って歌って踊るからね。
Got it. Well, we'll do our best to sing and dance!
踊れー！
Go for it!
頑張るぞー。みんな本当に、あのね、スンッて終わるから。多分。
Let's do this! Everyone, really, it's gonna end in a flash. Probably.
多分スンッて終わるから、みんな本当に今日来てくれてありがとねって言っとく。
It'll probably end in a flash, so I want to say thank you to everyone for coming today.
ありがとう。ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you.
おにぎりゃーさんも。ホロリスキー、おにぎりゃーありがとう。
Onigiri-ya-san too. Holorisky, Onigiri-ya, thank you.
ありがとうね。本当にありがとう。
Thanks everyone. Really, thank you.
では次行きますか。頑張って歌います。
Well, shall we move on to the next one? We'll do our best.
おかころ2周年本当に、本当にありがとう！
OkaKoro 2nd Anniversary... thank you so, so much!
頑張るぞー。
Let's do our best!
では最後の曲。
Now then, for the last song...
はい。
Yes.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
チルノのパーフェクトさんすう教室！
Cirno's Perfect Math Class!
みんなー！ チルノのさんすう教室、 始まるよ！
Everyone! Cirno's Math Class is starting!
あたいみたいな天才目指して、 頑張っていってね！
Aim to be a genius like me and do your best!
チルノのパーフェクトさんすう教室
作詞 夕野ヨシミ / 作曲 ZUN
Cirno's Perfect Math Class
Lyrics: Yoshimi Yuuno / Composition: ZUN
キラキラ ダイアモンド
Sparkling diamond
輝く星のように
Like a shining star
栄光、勝利、功、 なんとかして入ろう
Glory, victory, success, let's get in somehow
天才秀才トップ目指して GO!
Aim for the top as geniuses and prodigies, GO!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
ちょっ、違うわ！バカじゃないもん！
Hey, wait! I'm not an idiot!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
バカって言うほうがバカなんですのよ！
The one who calls others idiots is the idiot!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
何よ！うるさいわね、このバカ！
What! Shut up, you idiot!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
おまけのニャ 間違えて 初めに3人乗りました
Bonus meow, by mistake, three people got on first
白黒で 1人降りて 8人だけ乗りました
At the black and white stop, one got off, and eight were left
八雲さんちで 2人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ？
Two got off at Yakumo's house, so how many passengers are left in total?
答えは答えは 0人0人
The answer is, the answer is: zero, zero!
なぜならなぜなら それは幻想郷にはバスない
Because, because, there are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち 意味などないわ キャラクター 立てばいいのよ
Climax, resolution, they're meaningless.
As long as the character stands out, it's fine
元気があれば何でも 1、2、キュッ！
If you've got energy, you can do anything!
One, two, nine!
くるくると時計の針 くるくるあたま回る
Round and round the clock hands go,
round and round my head spins
たって つぺろめた は 2つしかないのに
3本の針ってちんぷんかん
Even though a thermometer only has two points,
three hands are just gibberish
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problems come one after another,
the class goes on and on
凍る部屋の中 冷やした温度も 時間も気にせず
ゆっくりしていってね！
In the freezing room, without worrying about
the temperature or time, take it easy!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ！
I'm telling you, I'm not an idiot!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
いい加減にしないと冷凍するわよ！
Stop it, or I'll freeze you!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
そして粉々になって死ねばいいのよ！
And then you can just shatter and die!
レミリアの 100万円の 壺を誰かが割っちゃった
Someone broke Remilia's one million yen vase
永遠亭の 永琳が 弁償しに来ましたよ
Eirin from Eientei came to pay for the damages
知らんぷりの 居眠り 結局弁償金額いくら？
Pretending not to notice, taking a nap.
So how much is the compensation?
答えは答えは 0円0円
The answer is, the answer is: zero yen, zero yen!
なぜならなぜなら そんな壺あるわけない
Because, because, there's no way such a vase exists!
常識 超えたところに 世界の真理はある
The truth of the world lies beyond common sense
秘密の数式目指して 1、2、キュッ！
Aim for the secret formula! One, two, nine!
へらへらニヤけながら ゲラゲラ笑いながら
With a silly grin, laughing out loud
うっざい ればうさぎ 可愛げもないのに
新参の連中はハイハイハイ
Annoying pests, even though they're not cute,
the newbies just go 'Yes, yes, yes!'
大声 100万回 漏れなくゴミなんて
Shout it out a million times,
without exception, everyone's trash
どういうことなのよ 散らかっているなら
さあバカにお疲れさんって言っとけ！
What do you mean? If it's messy,
just say 'Good job' to the idiots!
わかった！あたいがあまりにも天才だから、 嫉妬してるんでしょ！
I get it! You're just jealous because I'm such a genius!
ほんとしょうがないわね、特別に、
あたいの天才の秘訣をちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ！
Really, there's no helping it. I'll give you a special treat
and teach you a bit of the secret to my genius!
アライライ... 英知を集めて束ねても
Gathering and bundling all the wisdom
アタイの... 宇宙一の頭に敵わない
Can't compete with my number one brain in the universe
アムシャ... 食べたら顎がひねる
If you eat it, your jaw will twist
アタイは... 完璧いわゆるパーフェクト！
I am perfect, the so-called perfect!
100億兆万バッチリ！
One hundred billion trillion million perfect!
山落ち 意味などないわ キャラクター 立てばいいのよ
Climax, resolution, they're meaningless.
As long as the character stands out, it's fine
元気があれば何でも 1、2、キュッ！
If you've got energy, you can do anything!
One, two, nine!
くるくると時計の針 くるくるあたま回る
Round and round the clock hands go,
round and round my head spins
たって つぺろめた は 2つしかないのに
3本の針ってちんぷんかん
Even though a thermometer only has two points,
three hands are just gibberish
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く
Problems come one after another,
the class goes on and on
凍る部屋の中 冷やした温度も 時間も気にせず
ゆっくりしていってね！
In the freezing room, without worrying about
the temperature or time, take it easy!
バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！ バーカバーカ！
Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot! Idiot, idiot!
もうバカっていいわよ知らない！
I don't care about being called an idiot anymore!
1、2、キュッ！
One, two, nine!
おかころ2周年LIVE
OkaKoro 2nd Anniversary LIVE
おかころ 2周年 LIVE